hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says x^2 + IX + 2 = 0 and it wants us to
solve for x this I coefficient can be
thought of two different ways you can
think of it as i^2 is equal to -1 or I
is equal to the < TK of1 it's called the
imaginary number and you can do a lot of
useful things with this I but for this
video I was wondering can we use
quadratic formula to solve this
quadratic if the coefficient is
imaginary let's try it out so a is the
coefficient for x^2 and up here that
would be an implied one so in the place
of this a we can plug in one and the
same thing for this A and B is the
coefficient for X this is where the I
comes in so in the place of this B we
can plug in I and we can do the same
thing to this B and last C is the
constant which is two up here so we can
change this C to two and now we can
clean things up let's copy down the
negative I and the plus or minus and the
square root and for this I squ we know
that i^2 is equal to -1 so I'm going to
change this to -1 and then we're going
to subtract 4 * 1 1 * 2 which is equal
to 8 and then on bottom the 2 * 1 is
equal to 2 next let's focus on this
radical we have -1 - 8 which is equal to
9 we can split up this < tk9 to beunk 1
* < tk9 and now this Ro tk1 if we look
up here is equal to I so we can change
this into I and then theun 9 is equal to
3 so now we have X is equal to i+ or - 3
i/ 2 This plus or minus is giving us two
solutions we have one for the plus and
one for the minus and now for the first
one I + 3 I is equal to 2 I and 2 / 2
cancel each other out so we have x = i
for the first one and for this one I - 3
I is -4 I and -4 / 2 is -2 so the other
solution is -2 I so the quadratic
formula did seem to work but let's check
our answers let's copy down the original
equation and in the place of both of
these X's we want to plug in -2 I for
the first term term -2 i^ 2 the squar is
going to go both to the -2 and to the I
and then for the second term we can
bring down the -2 and I * I is equal to
i^ 2 and the rest of this can be brought
down and then before we move on -22 is
the same thing as -2 * -2 which is equal
to pos4 for the next step let's copy
this down and then i^2 is equal to -1 so
in the place of both of these I squ we
can plug in -1 4 * -1 is -4 and -2 * -1
is pos2 and then -4 + 2 + 2 is equal 0
so we end up with 0 equal 0 so the first
one checks out so now let's check the
second one in the place of both of these
X's we can plug in I so we end up with
i^2 + i^2 + 2 = 0 and then i^ 2 is equal
to 1 so each of these I squar can change
into 1 and then - 1 +1 + 2 is equal to 0
so we end up with 0 equals 0 and the
second one checks out so the quadratic
formula did work for an imagin
coefficient and we now have our answers
let's put a box around them how exciting